<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Nawaf's Portfolio</title><link>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Nawaf's Portfolio</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 08:01:10 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How eyLog Manages Mobile Releases</title><link>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/how-eylog-manages-mobile-releases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 08:01:10 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/how-eylog-manages-mobile-releases/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="context">&lt;strong>Context&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Consistently launching updates on the App Store and Play Store can be more complicated than it seems, particularly managing multiple apps at the same time. Exploring the workflows of different teams is fascinating. By identifying commonalities and distinctions, we can uncover potentially beneficial strategies. Here is an overview of eyLog&amp;rsquo;s mobile release management.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="overview-of-release-cycle">&lt;strong>Overview of Release cycle&lt;/strong>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Our release cycles are pretty similar to what many other companies do. Here’s a quick look at how we handle things:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Optimizing Cache Management Strategy in Beeda</title><link>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/cache-management-strategy-in-beeda/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 08:01:10 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/cache-management-strategy-in-beeda/</guid><description>&lt;p>To deliver a fast and seamless user experience, every application requires an effective caching system. Without caching, repeatedly downloading assets can consume significant resources and cause delays in loading times. To overcome this, developers use a variety of caching strategies, including &lt;strong>disk caching&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>LRU (Least Recently Used) caching&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>database caching&lt;/strong>, and others, to enhance performance and minimize latency.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h3 id="problem">Problem:&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In the &lt;strong>Beeda User&lt;/strong> app, effectively handling media assets like images, Lottie animations, and videos was essential for ensuring a fast and seamless user experience. Each type of media asset comes with its own specific needs and challenges when it comes to caching and optimization:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving Beeda's Swift Compilation times by 83%</title><link>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/improving-beedas-swift-compilation-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 08:01:47 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://chowdhurynawaf.github.io/en/posts/improving-beedas-swift-compilation-time/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context">Context&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As Beeda expanded with new features, compile times began to pose a serious challenge. A simple change or full compilation took around 11 minutes, slowing down our workflow significantly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To enhance productivity and streamline development, we aimed to drastically reduce this compile time. In this article, I’ll walk you through how we successfully brought it down to just 2 minutes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="optimization-levels-in-xcode">Optimization Levels in Xcode&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Xcode provides three optimization levels to choose from:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>